uh welcome everyone to day two of bioc asia uh before we begin today uh i'd just like to
BioC Asia の 2 日目へようこそみなさん。今日開始する前に
celebrate and acknowledge the traditional owners and custodians in the land of on which i'm joining
私が居る土地の伝統的な所有者と管理人を祝福し、感謝したいと思います。
you from today here in melbourne australia which are the raundry people of the kulin nation i pay
ここオーストラリア メルボルンではクリン民族の人たちがその人たちに相当します。
my respects to their elders past and present and embrace their continued connection to this place
私は彼らの過去と現在の年配の方たちに敬意を表し、この場所への彼らの継続的な(思想の)つながりを受け入れます。
i'd also like to extend this respect to elders from other communities where people are joining
また、人々が参加している他のコミュニティの年配の方たちにもこの敬意を表したいと思います。
us from today sovereignty has never been seated this is and always has been aboriginal land
主権の座には就いていませんがここは常にアボリジニの土地です。
today uh we're going to begin with a couple of talks from the bioconductor core team
今日は、Bioconductor のコアチームからのいくつかの講演から始めます。
so from lori shepard and from the tisch so laurie's talk has been video recorded and has
そんなわけで Lori Shepherd と Nitesh からです。 Lori のトークはビデオ録画物になります。
japanese subtitles to enable those japanese speakers to follow the talk as well
そしてそれは日本語の字幕を持っており、日本語話者も話を追えるようになっています。
and in an attempt to make this talk even more accessible i'm going
またこのトークをよりアクセシブルにしようと思い、
to briefly switch to uh japanese uh so please forgive my friends pronunciation but uh
私は一時的に日本語に切り替えを行いたいと思います。発音についてはご容赦ください。
hello everyone i hope you're enjoying bioc asia 2021 i'd like to thank the conference organizers
こんにちは、みなさん。 BioC Asia 2021を楽しんでいらっしゃることと思います。
for inviting me to speak today and while this isn't live i'm very excited to be giving my first
本日は、カンファレンスの主催者から講演の招待をいただきありがとうございます。
keynote talk ever my talk today is on bioconductor what bioconductor is and how the core team helps
これはライブトークではありませんが私の初めてのキーノートトークでありとてもわくわくしています。今日の私のトークはBioconductorについてです。
facilitate the project so the first thing that surprised me when i started going to more
Bioconductorとは何か、そしてそのコアチームがBioconductorというプロジェクトをどのように支援しているかを紹介します。
general r and computing conferences was the misconception that bioconductor was a single
私が一般的なRおよびコンピューティングの会議に参加し始めたときに最初に驚いたのは、Bioconductorが単一のRパッケージであるという誤解でした。
r package and the bioconductor project is much larger than a single package bioconductor
Bioconductorプロジェクトは、単一のパッケージではなく、それよりはるかに大きいものです。
is an open source and open development r package repository system that focuses on
Bioconductorは、オープンソースおよびオープン開発のRパッケージリポジトリシステムです。
analysis comprehension and visualization of genetic and genomic data there are actually
それは遺伝学およびゲノミクスデータの分析、理解、および視覚化を中心に扱っています。
currently over 2000 software packages in addition to specialized data experiment
Bioconductorには現在2000を超えるパッケージがあります。
annotation and workflow packages that are available through the bioconductor interface
加えて専門的な実験やアノテーションのデータやワークフローもあります。それらはBioconductorのインターフェースを通じて利用できます。
but bioconductor is more than just a package repository system it really is a well-developed
ただし、Bioconductorは単なるパッケージリポジトリシステムではありません。
organization and there are many people involved with shaping the direction of the project
それは真に巧妙に築き上げられた組織です。多くの人が関わりプロジェクトの方向性を決めています。
currently there are three main advisory boards the scientific technical and community boards
現在、「科学」「技術」「コミュニティ」の3つの主要な諮問委員会があります。
the scientific advisory board is an invitation only board that provides external guidance
科学諮問委員会は招待されたメンバーのみの委員会です。
and oversight on the scientific direction of the project the technical and community advisory
それはプロジェクトの科学的方向性に関する外部の助言と監視を提供します。
boards however have open public elections every spring for inclusion on the board
一方コミュニティ諮問委員会は毎年春に委員会に加わるためのオープンな公開投票によって選出されます。
the technical advisory board advises on project and package level infrastructure
技術諮問委員会はプロジェクトおよびパッケージレベルのインフラストラクチャについてアドバイスします。
while the community advisory board is really dedicated to developing enhancing and diversifying
一方、コミュニティ諮問委員会はBioconductorコミュニティの発展、強化、および多様化に取り組んでいます。
the bioconductor community anyone can run for a position on these two boards for the technical
誰でもこれらの2つの委員会のポジションに立候補することができます。
board it may be useful to have some finer knowledge of bioconductor and programming
技術委員会の場合は、Bioconductorとプログラミングの知識や
or a specialized scientific technology background but the community board especially really wants
専門的な科学技術の背景があると便利かもしれません
to try and be as diverse as possible and aims for a mix of races ethnicity education level
コミュニティ委員会は特に、人種、民族、教育レベルそしてBioconductorの経験の組み合わせを目指して、可能な限り多様化を図りたいと考えています。
and bioconductor experience so if you're interested look for a call for applications
興味がある場合は、
on the bioconductor support site and community slack channel in early spring
春先にBioconductorのサポートサイトとコミュニティSlackチャンネルで志願の募集を探してください。
so thinking back on how this started that bioconductor is more than just a single package
Bioconductorは単なる単一のパッケージではなくそれ以上のものであるという話に戻りましょう。
it's a package repository and an organization but even more importantly than that probably most
Bioconductorはパッケージリポジトリであり組織でもありますが、さらに重要なのは、おそらく最も重要なことですが
important it's a community so bioconductor really aims at trying to provide resources
コミュニティであるということです。そのためBioconductorは次の目的のためにリソースやインフラを提供しようとがんばっています。
and infrastructure to link experienced package maintainers developers and users
それは経験豊富なパッケージメンテナ、開発者、およびユーザーを、
with the inexperience to foster this collaborative and welcoming community of
経験の浅い人々とリンクさせ、この協力的で歓迎的なコミュニティを育成するためです。
our bioconductor users so how and where does this community connect well there are a couple
ではBioconductorユーザーはどのように、どこでコミュニティとつながるのでしょうか?
different places most notably the bioconductor support site the community slack channels and
それにはいくつかの異なる場所があります。注目すべきはBioconductorのサポートサイトとコミュニティSlackチャンネルそして
numerous conference workshops and training events that happen through the year and also a newly
数多く存在するカンファレンスワークショップとトレーニングイベントです。ワークショップとイベントは年を通じて起こっています。
developed mentoring chip program and i can just take you briefly through each of those right now
また新しく展開されたメンターシッププログラムもあります。私は今あなたにそれらそれぞれを簡単に說明できます。
the bioconductor support site is the first place many users go to ask questions and get
Bioconductorのサポートサイトは多くのユーザーが行く最初の場所です。
advice on analysis or to troubleshoot using bioconductor packages this support site is
そこではBioconductorパッケージを用いた解析やトラブルシュートの質問をし、アドバイスをもらいます。
specialized to bioconductor package questions and every maintainer that submits a package to
このサポートサイトはBioconductorパッケージの質問に特化しています。そしてBioconductorにパッケージを提出したすべてのメンテナーは
bioconductor is required to sign up so that if an ask question gets tagged with their package name
サポートサイトにサインアップする必要があります。もしメンテナーのパッケージ名でタグ付けされた質問が来たら
they would be notified there are thousands of users on here and it can be a great resource
メンテナーにはその通知が来るようになっています。サポートサイトには何千人ものユーザーがいます。
to tap into community knowledge and experience so you can search by clicking on a package tag or you
サポートサイトはコミュニティの知識と経験を活用するための優れたリソースになりえます。パッケージのタグをクリックすると検索ができます。
could go to the tags tab and search for a package to see what already existing posts and questions
またはタグのタブに移動してパッケージを検索することもできます。そして既存の投稿や質問を見ることができます。
are available if you don't see anything relevant to what you need you can always
もしあなたが必要とするものに関係のある何かが見つからなければ
post a new question by clicking on the ask a questions tab make sure to have an informative
あなたは新しい質問を投稿できます。ask a questionタブをクリックすることでそれができます。
title and be sure to tag any relevant packages that the question relates to in the post tags
有益なタイトルと質問に関連するパッケージのタグを投稿に付けるようにしてください。
the body uses markdown or plain text or html if you're having issues or errors running code be
本文には Markdown もしくはプレーンテキストまたはHTMLを使用します。もし問題、コード実行のエラーがある場合
sure to post as much of the code example in the code section and always include the platform and
できるだけ多くのコード例をコードセクションに含めてください。また必ずプラットフォームの情報、
version of r and bioconductor you are using so we can tailor the responses appropriately
RとBioconductorのバージョンも含めてください。すると我々が回答を適切に調整できるので。
the bioconductor team also uses the news feature to post important announcements for releases
Bioconductorチームはニュース機能を使って重要なアナウンスを投稿します。
packages conferences elections and other such news events
それはリリース、パッケージ、カンファレンス、選挙、およびその他のニュースイベントのためのものです。
there's also the bioconductor community slack channel and i really encourage everyone to join
BioconductorコミュニティのSlackチャンネルもあります。私はみなさんにそのチャンネルに参加することをおすすめします。
the channel as it is great for conversation there are a number of specialized channels that may be
そこには多くの特定の議論に役立つチャンネルがあります。
useful for a very particular discussion like microbiome metabolomics a proteomics channel
例えばマイクロバイオーム、メタボロミクス、プロテオミクスといったようなチャンネルがあります。
we also have channels to ask about core infrastructure pieces that we'll discuss a little
後で説明するコアインフラストラクチャの部分について質問するチャネルもありますが、
bit later on but channels like the bioc builds for build system questions or biosee hubs for
ビルドシステムの質問用のbioc-buildsや、
questions unlike experiment hub annotation hub or bioc file cache there are a number of conferences
experimenthub、annotationhub、またはbiocfilecacheの質問用のbiochubsなどのチャネルもあります。
workshops and training events throughout the year there's a bioconductor event calendar
年間を通じて多くのカンファレンス、ワークショップ、トレーニングイベントがあります。
off the main website that anyone can submit bioconductor related events to advertise anyone
メインのウェブサイトにはBioconductorイベントカレンダーがあり、誰でもBioconductor関連のイベントを送信して宣伝できます。
is welcome to submit event for inclusion on the page either by emailing events at bioconductor.org
events@bioconductor.org に電子メールを送信するか
or we're working on a forum version that should be available soon minimum requirements for an event
まもなく利用可能になるフォーム版で、誰でもウェブページに含めるイベントを送信できます。
is a relevance to bioconductor and a willingness to adhere to the bioconductor code of conduct
イベントの最小要件はBioconductorとの関連性、およびBioconductor行動規範を守ることです。
conferences are always a good time and a great way to meet other members of the community and network
カンファレンスは常に楽しい時であり、コミュニティやネットワークの他のメンバーと会うための素晴らしい方法です。
hopefully you are all enjoying yourselves here at bioc asia which has become an annual event
毎年恒例のイベントとなっている、このBioCAsiaを楽しんでいただければ幸いです。
there's also the annual maine bios conference normally held in the united states in late summer
また、夏の終わりに米国で通常開催されるメインのBioCカンファレンスと、
and the annual eurobiose conference and the next currently one scheduled is for march 2022
毎年恒例のEuroBioCカンファレンスがあり、現在予定されている次のカンファレンスは2022年3月です。
in recent years we are excited to see initiatives in other countries as well that bioconductor is
近年、他の国でもBioconductorのイニシアチブが見られることに興奮しています。
glad to send representatives and be a part of the community of bioinformatics software developers in
Bioconductorはその代表者をバイオインフォマティクスソフトウェア開発者のコミュニティの一部に喜んで送っています。
mexico and latin america have started organizing yearly week-long workshops and various conference
具体的には毎年1週間にわたるメキシコとラテンアメリカの
and workshops throughout the year to aid in development of the spanish-speaking armed
スペイン語でのカンファレンスやワークショップですとか
bioconnector community and the h3a bionet and h3a africa launched a series of workshops and webinars
ワークショップやウェビナーのシリーズとして立ち上げられたH3ABioNetそしてH3Africaに代表者を送っています。
to help advance the african coding and research communities which bioconductor took part in also
アフリカの人がコーディングや研究を促進するのを助けるものです。
these again are just a few of the many workshops webinars and training opportunities
これらはBioconductorが加わっている多くのワークショップやウェビナーそしてトレーニングの機会のほんの一部です。
launched around the world throughout the year and we are really excited to see
それらは年間を通じて世界中で立ち上げられており、
that the bioconnector community is growing and that we can be a part of research worldwide
Bioconductorコミュニティが成長し、私たちがワールドワイドな研究の一部になれていることに本当に興奮しています。
so those are some great resources to connect to the community but now i want to take it back to
ところでそれらはコミュニティとつながるすばらしいリソースですが、
this slide on organization just for a second because we skipped over the last entry the
ちょっと前の組織のスライドに戻りたいと思います。なぜなら私たちはその最後のエントリーであるコアチームをスキップしたので。
core team the core team plays a vital role in the functionality of the project it's a small
コアチームは、プロジェクトの機能において重要な役割を果たします。
dedicated group of developers that help develop maintain and enhance core packages and project
それは小さな特化された開発者のグループで、コアパッケージとプロジェクトレベルのインフラストラクチャの開発、保守、強化を支援します。
level infrastructure so what does that really mean i get the feeling that most people think that the
それが本当に意味していることはどのようなことでしょうか? ほとんどの人は次のように考えていると思います。
core team only takes care of core packages and package maintenance but we really do so
「コアチームはコアパッケージとパッケージメンテナンスだけ管理している」と。しかし実際には我々は
much more than that we talked about bioconductor being a project there's a lot of infrastructure
それよりもっと多くのことを行っています。私たちはBioconductorがプロジェクトであることについて話しました。そこには多くのインフラストラクチャの要素があります。
pieces that are in place to make the project function so thinking about the resources we
それらはプロジェクトを機能させるためにあります。それではそのリソースについて考えてみましょう。
just went over what core infrastructure is involved that the core team maintains
私たちは今しがたコアインフラストラクチャがコアチームが保守しているものに含まれることを見直しました。
so first there's the main website bioconductor.org the core team is responsible for updates and
そんなわけでまずコアチームが更新と維持を行う責任があるものとしてメインのウェブサイト bioconductor.org があります。
website upkeep there's an entire code base for the website and the website is
ウェブサイトは完全にコードベースで
regenerated about every 20 minutes to make sure that there is constant up-to-date information
約20分毎に再生成され、常に最新の情報が確認できるようになっています。
similarly there's a code base for the support site website we thankfully have support and help from
同様にサポートサイトのウェブサイトもコードベースです。ありがたいことに私たちは
the biostars that our support site is modeled after and in particular an attay that assists
サポートサイトのモデルとしたBiostars、特にNatay Aberraからのサポートと助けを得ています。
but we still have core team involvement in the upkeep and maintenance of that site
ですがサポートサイトの維持とメンテナンスにはコアチームが関与しています。
there's also monitoring and answering questions that appear on the community
またコミュニティSlackチャンネルに現れる質問を監視・解決してもいます。
slack channels many times resulting in follow-up and investigation of issues comments and concerns
多くの場合に問題、コメント、懸念のフォローアップや調査につながっています。
and many core team members participate in presenting material for conferences and workshops
また、多くのコアチームメンバーがカンファレンスやワークショップの資料のプレゼンに参加しています。
there's also normally components of the conference like specialized web pages systems for hosting
普通のカンファレンスのコンポーネントに関与している場合もあります。例えばワークショップをホストするための専用のウェブページですとか
workshops and having computer environments for participants that the core team also helps manage
参加者のためのコンピューター環境を用意するなどです。そんな具合にもコアチームは
and facilitate so hopefully you can already see the importance of this back-end infrastructure so
管理や促進を助けています。そんなわけでみなさんはもうバックエンドのインフラストラクチャの重要性をお分かりになられたかと思います。
continuing on i want to think about bioconductor from two perspectives a user and a developer
続いて、ユーザーと開発者の2つの視点からBioconductorについて考えていきたいと思います。
and along the way we'll discuss additional important project infrastructure that the
これまでに私たちは付加的な重要なプロジェクトインフラについて議論してきました。
core team helps develop maintain and enhance to try to provide a good experience to the community
それはコアチームがコミュニティにいい体験を提供するために維持と強化の発展を支援しているものです。
so thinking about a user how does a user interact with bioconductor traditionally
それではユーザーがどのようにBioconductorとインタラクトするか考えてみましょう。
i think most users were using our terminal or rstudio which is still highly popular and
従来ほとんどのユーザーはターミナルやRStudioを使っていたかと思います。それらは依然としてとても人気があり
widely utilized but there are also newer available technologies and projects like using docker images
広く利用されていますが、より新しい利用可能なテクノロジーとプロジェクトがあります。たとえばDockerイメージですとか
or cloud-based initiatives like the anvil project that allow a different user experience
クラウドベースの新たな取り組みです。AnVILプロジェクトはターミナルやRStudioとは異なるユーザーエクスペリエンスを実現するものです。
for our terminal and rstudio users there's a cram package bioc manager that is downloaded
ターミナルやRStudioのユーザー用にはCRANパッケージのBiocManagerがあります。
installed from cran and provides access to all packages in bioconductor and crayon repositories
それはCRANからインストールできすべてのBioconductorとCRANパッケージへのアクセスを提供します。
the anvil which stands for analysis visualization and informative lab space is an nhgri project
Analysis Visualization and Informative Lab-spaceの略であるAnVILはNHGRI(訳注: 米国国立ヒトゲノム研究所)のプロジェクトです。
it provides a secure cloud-based computing environment for analysis i will not go into
それは分析用の安全なクラウドベースのコンピューティング環境を提供します。
detail here about anvil and docker images but i encourage everyone to attend natashas talk where
ここではAnVILとDockerイメージについて詳しくは説明しませんが、みなさんには次のNiteshのトークに参加されることをお勧めします。
i believe some of these concepts and resources will be covered i will mention that the anvil
そこではAnVILのコンセプトやリソースがカバーされていると思います。私の方ではAnVILについて次のことだけ述べます。
bioconductor package provides a different install function designed specifically for
それはAnVILのBioconductorパッケージは異なるインストール機能をもたらすということです。
use with the bioconductor docker images and the anvil computing space that can provide fast binary
それは Bioconductor の Docker イメージと AnVIL の計算環境で使うことに特化してデザインされています。AnVILの計算環境は
package installation why is this significant well some packages require compilation which can take
それは高速なバイナリパッケージのインストール方法を実現しています。なぜこれが重要かというといくつかのパッケージはコンパイルを必要とするからです。
several seconds package binaries are pre-compiled allowing for a near instantaneous installation the
コンパイルには時間がかかりますが、バイナリパッケージはコンパイル済みなのでほぼ一瞬でインストールできるようになります。
limitation of binaries is that package binaries are specific to the system configuration to which
ただバイナリパッケージの制約はそのシステム構成に特化されているということです。
they were generated which is why they're only available for use with the docker
それはバイナリパッケージが作られた環境でしか動きません。そんなわけでバイナリパッケージはDockerを用いた環境でしか利用できません。
another important concept for users especially new users is how to find packages of interest
ユーザー、特に新規ユーザーにとってのもう1つの重要な概念は、関心のあるパッケージを見つける方法です。
in bios manager there's a function available that shows a listing of all available packages
BiocManagerには、利用可能なすべてのパッケージのリストを表示する機能があります。
or you could use a search term to find packages but that assumes some a priori knowledge the
または、検索語を使用してパッケージを見つけることもできます。ですがそれは事前知識を想定しています。
bioc views page and package landing pages can be really useful for finding packages
biocViews ページとパッケージライディングページは、パッケージを見つけるのに非常に役立ちます。
off the bioconductor.org home page there's a link to available software packages
bioconductor.org ホームページから離れます。利用可能なソフトウェアパッケージへのリンクがあります。
this takes you to what we call our bioseed views page and includes software annotation experiment
このリンクは私たちが「biocViews」と呼んでいるページへあなたを連れていきます。そしてそれは「software」「annotation」「experiment」
and workflow packages books are coming soon you can either search for terms of interest
加えて「workflow」パッケージを含んでいます。「books」パッケージという近日登場予定のカテゴリもあります。興味のある用語でもパッケージを検索できます。
like single cell or proteomics to get a list of packages or if you know a package name
例えば single cell や proteomics といったものでパッケージのリストを取得できます。またもしあなたがパッケージ名を知っているなら
you can search for it specifically like genomic ranges or summarized experiment
それを明確に検索できます。例えば「GenomicRanges」や「SummarizedExperiment」といったように。
the rank ordering is in order of most downloaded to lease downloaded and if you click on a package
「Rank」の順は最もダウンロードされたものからわずかにしかダウンロードされていないものへの順になっています。パッケージ名をクリックすると
name it takes you to a bioconductor's package landing page the page has badges to indicate
Bioconductorのパッケージランディングページへ導かれます。そのページはパッケージの健全性などを示すバッジを持っています。
package health and information on the package like the description documentation what package
またパッケージについての情報も持っています。例えば説明、ドキュメンテーション、
dependencies or reverse dependencies there are and in the bottom a link to download the package
パッケージ依存、または逆依存といったものです。また最後尾にはBiocManagerを使わずにパッケージを直接ダウンロードするためのリンクと
directly instead of through bioc manager access to the code base in git.bioconductor.org and package
git.bioconductor.org 中のコードベース、そしてパッケージダウンロード統計にアクセスするためのリンクがあります。
download statistics probably the most helpful on this page is the package documentation that a user
このページでおそらくもっとも有用なのはパッケージのドキュメンテーションです。
can browse through before downloading a package to see if it's appropriate for their type of analysis
それはユーザーがパッケージをダウンロードする前にざっと目を通し、そのパッケージがユーザーの解析のタイプに合っているかを確認できるようになっています。
so before switching to a developer's point of view let's revisit the core team
それでは開発者の視点にスイッチする前に、
and in these few concepts for users what sort of infrastructure is required in the background
コアチームと、ユーザーにとってどんな類のインフラがバックグラウンドで必要とされるかを再検討してみましょう。
so there's obviously some package maintenance with regard to bioc manager anvil anvil specific
そこには明らかにいくつかのパッケージメンテナンス作業があります。 BiocManager に関するもの、AnVIL 固有のもの、
packages and bioseat views packages there's a concept of a daily build of all bioconductor
biocViewsのパッケージに関するものといったようにです。すべてのBioconductorパッケージにはデイリービルドの概念があります。
packages so that they're available through the bioc manager install function there's generation
そのためパッケージはBiocManager::install関数で利用できるようになっているのです。
and upkeep of docker images so bioconductor docker images for both release and develop branches
Docker イメージの生成と維持もあります。 Bioconductor のDocker イメージは release と develop ブランチの両方のものがあり、
and an anvil specific docker image that needs to be submitted to the anvil platform
さらには AnVIL プラットフォームに提出する必要がある AnVIL 固有の Docker イメージがあります。
there's also the binary package generation for those provide packages provided through
また AnVIL::install を使って提供されるパッケージのバイナリパッケージ生成もあります。
anvil install and then there's the website code and website interaction so that you
その上ウェブサイトのコードとウェブサイトのインタラクションもあります。
could see that biosea views page and package landing pages and the constant regeneration
それによってあなたは biocViews のパージとパッケージランディングページを見ることができているわけです。
of the website to make sure that all that information stays up to date to the latest
また定期的なウェブサイトの再生成は、その情報を時代遅れにせず最新状態で居続けることを確かにしています。
and then at the bottom of the packing landing pages i mentioned it briefly but there's package
また、パッケージのランディングページの最後尾で簡単に説明しましたが、
download statistics that get calculated for each package as well so again hopefully that you can
パッケージごとに算出されるダウンロード統計もあります。繰り返しになりますが
see while it may seem like trivial and basic functionality that there's a lot that needs to
些細で基本的な機能に見える一方で
be in place behind the scenes for everything to function properly and interact properly
すべてが適切に機能し適切にインタラクトするには、舞台裏で行う必要のあることが大量にあることがお分かりになるかと思います。
so the core team has a subset of packages that are considered core packages and core
コアチームはあるパッケージのサブセットを持っています。それは「コアパッケージ」と考えられ、
team maintained but most of the packages in bioconductor are community contributed
「コアチームによってメンテされている」ものです。ですがBioconductorのほとんどのパッケージはコミュニティの貢献によるものです。
anyone from the community is welcome to develop and submit a package to bioconductor
コミュニティの誰もが Bioconductor パッケージを開発して提出することを歓迎します。
there are certain specific package requirements that should be implemented when developing
開発時に実装する必要がある特定のパッケージ要件があり、パッケージはレビュープロセスを受けます。 パッケージを開発する場合いくらかの必要条件があります。
and a package will undergo a review process once a package is accepted
そしてパッケージはレビュープロセスに経ます。一旦パッケージがアクセプトされると、
then it's added to the daily builder and available through bioc manager install
それはデイリービルダーに追加され、BiocManagerを使ってインストールできるようになります。
so package specific requirements can be found at contributions.bioconnector.org
パッケージの必要条件は contributions.bioconductor.org で見つけることができます。
and the developer section of the main website we are in the process of moving information
また メインウェブサイトの developer セクションでも見つけることができます。
from the developer section of the website to the contributions.bioconductor.org location
現在 そのウェブサイトの developer セクションから contributions.bioconductor.org に情報を動かしている最中です。
so eventually all the information will be in one location
ですので最終的にすべての情報は1カ所にあるようになります。
but let's go over some of the key concepts that should be implemented when developing a package
パッケージを開発する時に実装する義務があるいくつかのキーコンセプトを見直してみましょう。
one of the main things is reusing or extending existing classes and using the well-developed
重要なことの1つは再利用もしくは既存クラスの拡張そして
import and export methods for certain data types bioconductor has the concept of interoperability
特定のデータタイプ用のimportとexportのメソッドがよく開発されているものを使うことです。Bioconductor は相互運用性の概念を持っており、
so if a user wants to use one package to import a different normalize and a third to visualize the
そのためあるユーザーが1つのパッケージを使い、異なるパッケージでノーマライズを行い、3つ目で可視化を行いたい場合、
manipulation of data from one package to the next should be minimal if not eliminated completely for
1つのパッケージから次のパッケージへのデータの操作は、もし完全に排除されていないなら最小限に留めるべきです。
the user so ideally the output of one should be the input to another this is why we like to
理想的には一方のパッケージの出力がもう一方のパッケージへの入力であるべきです。
emphasize using or extending any of the existing class structures another good practice worth
これが、私たちが既存のクラス構造の使用または拡張を強調したい理由です。
mentioning is the caching of web-based data when possible this way if a user is without internet or
言及する価値がある別のグッドプラクティスは、可能ならウェブベースデータのキャッシュを作ることです。これはあるユーザーがインターネットが使えない、もしくは
requests the same file from a website or a website is temporary unavailable they don't have to
あるウェブサイトから同じファイルにリクエストする、もしくはウェブサイトが一時的に利用できない場合に
re-download and could potentially use a previously downloaded version instead of having to wait for
再ダウンロードの必要が無く、前にダウンロードしたバージョンを
the internet or re-download data another good practice is implementing unit tests it's strongly
インターネットの復帰やデータの再ダウンロードを待つことなく使えるようにする可能性を秘めています。さらに別のグッドプラクティスはユニットテストの実装です。
recommended while tests can seem burdensome if added to the development process early it
テストは面倒に思えるかもしれませんがそれを強くお勧めします。もしテストを開発プロセスに早めに追加すると
can actually aid in development so testing for things like edge cases and having both positive
それは意外と開発に役立ち得ます。そんなわけでエッジケースなどをテストしたり
and negative tests can ensure proper proper functionality biggest thing that bioconductor
ポジ・ネガの両方のテストをしたりすると正常な機能を確保できます。
is also going to insist upon is a really detailed vignette with runnable code examples
加えてBioconductorが要求する大きなことは、実行可能な例を伴う実に詳細な vignette です。
so vignettes are compiled when built so it can also help ensure proper functioning code but we
vignette はパッケージがビルドされる時にコンパイルされます。そのため、 vignette はコードが適切に機能するかを保証するのにも役立ちます。
like detailed vignettes because ideally this gives your users an understanding of the package and
理想的には vignette がユーザーにそのパッケージとその固有の機能の理解を与えてくれるので、私たちは詳細な vignette を好みます。
the unique functionality that the package provides and these are just a few concepts of the many that
これらはあなたが contributions.bioconductor.org ページで見つけるであろう多くのコンセプトの内のほんの一部にすぎません。
you'll find on this contributions.bioconductor.org page so once a package is developed a user then
ひとまずパッケージが開発されるとユーザーは
submits to the bioconductor new submission tracker on github there's some useful information on the
GitHub上のBioconductorの新投稿トラッカーにそれを投稿します。そのホームページにはいくつかの有用な情報があります。
home page about what to expect and how to submit related or dependent packages
それは何を期待するか、ですとか どのように関連するもしくは依存するパッケージをどのように投稿するか、といったものです。
but to submit a new issue you go to open a new issue under bioconductor contributions the title
新しいイシューを投稿するには、 Bioconductor/Contributions 下で「New issue」開くように移動してください。
should be your package name all packages currently require a github repository location and the link
そのタイトルはあなたのパッケージ名である必要があります。すべてのパッケージは今のところGitHubのリポジトリの配置が必要です。
should be updated pointing to this location a package then is an awaiting moderation stage
そしてその場を指しつつリンク先のリポジトリが更新される必要があります。そしてパッケージがモデレーション段階待ちになります。
a reviewer will be assigned and the package added to our get.bioconductor.org location
そしてレビュアーがアサインされ、そのパッケージは私たちの git.bioconductor.org の場所に追加されます。
and a build triggered on all three major os platforms linux mac and windows once a package
そして3つのメジャーOSプラットフォーム Linux Mac Windows すべてでビルドがトリガーされます。
is building and checking without error the reviewer will do an in-depth review of the package
一度パッケージが "ERROR" が無くビルド・チェックされたら、レビュアーはそのパッケージのより詳しいレビューを行います。
and offer comments suggestions or request changes consistent with bioconductor package requirements
そして Bioconductor パッケージの必要条件と一致するようにコメントや提案、また変更リクエストを提示します。
there's an open dialogue in the review process open to the community and governed by the
レビュープロセスはコミュニティに開かれており、そこではオープンな意見交換があります。
bioconductor code of conduct once a package is accepted it's added to the nightly daily builder
またそれは Bioconductor の行動規範によって統治されています。一旦パッケージがアクセプトされるとそれはナイトリーデイリービルダーに追加されます。
bioconductor uses get for version control of package source code bioconductor builds only from
Bioconductor はパッケージのソースコードのバージョン管理に git を使います。
get.bioconductor.org and users must push changes to this location to propagate
Bioconductor は git.bioconductor.org からのみビルドされます。そしてユーザーはこの場所に変更をプッシュしそれをパッケージユーザーに伝播させる必要があります。
them to users from a few times a week to daily the bioconductor builders will do a get clone
週に数回から毎日程度の頻度で Bioconductor のビルダーはパッケージのあるバージョンを git clone を実行し
a version of the package and then do an r command install r command build and r command
その後R CMD INSTALL、R CMD build、そして R CMD check を実行します。
check if the package installs builds and checks cleanly and has a valid version bump for changes
もしパッケージのinstall、build、checkがきちんと進み、変更に対する有効なバージョンアップがされていれば、
the package is propagated and becomes available through the bioc manager install function
そのパッケージは伝播し、BiocManager::install 関数を使って利用できるようになります。
maintainers can find the build reports from the main website in the lower right corner
パッケージのメンテナーは、メインWebサイトの右下隅にマークされた「Build reports」からビルドレポートを得ることができます。
marked build reports this page indicates how frequently the builds take place
このページはそのビルドがどの程度の頻度で行われるかを表示します。
if we click on browse for any of the build reports you'll get a list of every bioconductor package
ビルドレポートのいずれかをクリックすると、全 Bioconductor パッケージと
and the status through each stage the top of the page has a time stamp to indicate when it
各ステージに至るまでのステータスのリストが表示されます。 ページのトップにはそれがいつ生成されたかを示すタイムスタンプがあり、
was generated and each package has information on the version git commit and get date that the
それぞれのパッケージは Git のコミットのバージョンとビルダーがそのレポートのために使われた日付の情報を持っています。
builder used for that report you can click on any stage indicator for more information and results
何らかのステージのインジケーターをクリックしてより多くの情報と結果を見ることができます。
so what infrastructure is needed for everything just discussed for submitting
それではパッケージを投稿するために今説明したすべてのものに必要なインフラストラクチャは何でしょうか?
a package well there's evaluating and updating of the package guidelines
パッケージガイドラインの評価と更新があるでしょう。
there's the code that interacts with the package submission process on github
また GitHub でのパッケージ投稿プロセスとインタラクトするコードもあるでしょう。
and code specific to the new submission process on each of the three develop builders
そして3つの開発ビルダーのそれぞれの新投稿プロセスに固有のコードもあるでしょう。
the core team also participates currently in package reviews for new submissions
コアチームは今のところ新しい投稿に対するパッケージレビューにも参加しています。
there is facilitating the entire bioconductor get ecosystem
Bioconductor の Git のエコシステム全体の促進もあります。
which includes the get.bioconductor.org main repository location for all of the
それは git.bioconductor.org や、すべての Bioconductor パッケージのメインのリポジトリの場所を含みます。
bioconductor packages a git contributions app that manages ssh credentials of users
GitContributions アプリはユーザーの ssh 証明書を管理するものです。
get a light application that manages which users have access to which packages and gut hooks that
Gitolite はどのユーザーがどのパッケージにアクセスできるようにするかを管理するアプリです。
respond to different triggering events there's also the bioconductor build system called the bbs
Git hooks は様々なトリガーイベントに反応するものです。また BBS と呼ばれる Bioconductor Build System もあります。
which is a large undertaking of the core team there are minimally six build machines that
それはコアチームの一大仕事です。 そこでは最小限に6つのビルドマシンがあり、
require system administration and the underlying code base on each to handle the get clone the r
それはシステム管理と次のそれぞれをハンドルするための基本的なコードベースを必要とします。
command install the r command build the r command check the package propagation and the generation
git clone、R CMD install、R CMD build、R CMD check、パッケージを伝播させること、そして
of the build reports and there's minimally six builders because for both the bioconductor release
ビルドレポートの生成です。そして最小限でも6つビルダーがある理由は
and bioconductor devel branches we cover the three main os platforms of mac linux and windows
Bioconductor の release と devel ブランチの両方用に、私たちは3つのOSプラットフォーム Mac、Linux そして Windowsをカバーしているからです。
so briefly i wanted to also touch upon why bioconductor has a release in a devel branch
簡単に、Bioconductor に release と devel ブランチがある理由についても触れたいと思います。
bioconductor is closely associated with r most years in spring r has a release bioconductor
Bioconductor は R と密接に関連しています。 ほとんどの年の春に、R はリリースされます。
then needs to update which version of r is being used for packages to insured
その R のリリースの次に Bioconductor は更新する必要があります。どのバージョンのRがパッケージで継続して適切に機能するのを保証するためにです。
continued proper functionality bioconductor has two releases of gear a spring and a fall
Bioconductorには、春と秋 年に2つのリリースがあります。
where the devel branch is released and becomes the new release from roughly late april and early may
そこでは devel ブランチが「リリースされて」次の新しい release ブランチになります。ざっくりと4月末から5月始めにかけて
when the new version of r is released both the bioconductor release and devel branch use that
新しいRのバージョンがリリースされるので、その Bioconductor の release と devel ブランチ両方は
stapled release version of r or our patched version in fall normally late october early
R の安定したバージョンもしくはパッチがあてられたバージョンを使うことになります。秋、通常は10月末か11月始めに
november bioconductor does a second release at this time the bioconductor release branch
Bioconductorは2番目のリリースを行います。 今のところ、その Bioconductor の release ブランチは
still uses that stable rr patch version but the devel bioconductor branch switches to use r devel
引き続き安定した R と R のパッチがあたったバージョンを使います。 ですがその devel ブランチは R の devel バージョンを使うようにしています。
in preparation for the next r release in spring having a devel branch allows maintainers to
次の春の R のリリースに備えるためです。devel ブランチを使用すると、メンテナーは
adapt to changes in base r as well as changes in any other dependent packages that they may have
base-r の変更だけでなく、被ることになるであろう他の依存パッケージの変更にも適応できるようになります。
and then have minimal disruption or downtime to the end user bioconductor
そしてエンドユーザーへの混乱やダウンタイムを最小限に抑えることができます。
encourage package maintainers to enhance and make major changes on the development branch
Bioconductor は、パッケージメンテナが開発ブランチで大きな変更を加えて、
and restrict changes on the release branch to minor bug corrections again also reasoning
リリースブランチでの変更をマイナーなバグ修正に限定することを奨励しています。
that there would be a place for development and potential breakage without affecting the end users
繰り返しになりますが、エンドユーザーに影響を与えることなく開発や破壊的変更を行える場所を設けたいという理由からです。
the core team is always extremely busy during release time and with release related tasks it
コアチームは、リリース期間中はリリース関連のタスクで常に非常に忙しいです。
involves updating versions of r and bioconductor on minimumly the six builders emailing maintainers
それは最低6つのビルダーで R と Bioconductor のバージョンを更新すること、
that ignored the build failure notifications to try and fix their packages to avoid deprecation
Bioconductorから廃止予定とされることや除去されることを避けるようにパッケージの修正を試みるためのビルド失敗の通知が無視されていることをメンテナーに伝えるeメール、
and removal from bioconductor reviewing the influx of newly submitted packages for inclusion
新たに投稿されたパッケージのレビュー、
fixing or modifying any core packages that require such attention adding release related
注意を必要とするコアパッケージの修正または変更、リリース関連のアノテーションリソースの追加、
annotation resources creating new branches on get.bioconductor.org for all the packages for
新しいリリースのすべてのパッケージに対する git.bioconductor.org での新しいブランチの作成、
the new release and collating all the news files from packages to generate the release announcement
そして、リリースアナウンスを生成するためのすべてのパッケージのNEWSファイルの照合などです。
there is another key infrastructure piece that the core team maintains that has gained increasing
コアチームがメンテしている、最近人気が上昇している、また別の重要なインフラの要素があります。
popularity in recent years the concept of the bioconductor hubs annotation hub and experiment
それは Bioconductor Hubs というコンセプトです。 具体的には AnnotationHub と ExperimentHub というものがあります。
hub as a brief background git does not allow large files and our current git system does not support
簡単な背景として、git は大きなファイルを許可せず、私たちの現在の git システムは git-lfs をサポートしていません。
get lfs which means there has to be an alternative way to provide large data sets to users
それは、ユーザーに大規模なデータセットを提供するための代替方法が必要であることを意味します。
bioconductor insists data to be hosted on a secure public or institutional server like
Bioconductorは、データを安全な公共または機関のサーバーでホストすることを主張しています。
zenodo amazon s3 buckets microsoft azure among other trusted sites or direct access to web
例えば Zenodo、Amazon S3 バケット、Microsoft Azure、他にも信頼できるサイト、もしくは
resources or databases if available like ensemble or ncbi rather than privately hosting data on say
もし可能なら GitHub や Dropbox などでデータをプライベートにホストするのではなく Ensemble や NCBI のようなウェブリソースなりデータベースへのダイレクトアクセスといったものです。
a github or dropbox if you're developing a package we encourage a discussion about data
もしあなたがパッケージを開発しているなら、私たちは他のプラットフォーム上でのデータホスティングについて議論するのをお勧めします。
hosting on other platforms on the bioslee dash devel r-projects.org developers mailing list
bioc-devel@r-project.org の開発者メーリングリストで議論していただけます。
if a maintainer does not have access to such a resource bioconductor provides
メンテナーがそのようなリソースにアクセスできない場合は、
an amazon s3 bucket for use we are however actively investigating a migration of location
Bioconductor は Amazon S3 バケットを使ってもらえるようにしています。また一方で私たちは Amazon S3 から Microsoft Azure への場所の移行を積極的に調査しています。
from amazon s3 to microsoft azure developers can download resources directly from the trusted sites
開発者は信頼できるサイトから直接リソースをダウンロードできますが、
but must implement a caching mechanism in the background and we highly recommend the
バックグラウンドでキャッシュメカニズムを実装する必要があります。
bioconductor core package bioc file cache the other alternative to downloading directly and
そこで私たちは Bioconductor のコアパッケージ BiocFileCache を強くお勧めします。
implementing bios you file cache is to list the data in the annotation hub or experiment hub
直接ダウンロードし、そしてBiocFileCacheを実装することの代替方法は、データを AnnotationHub もしくは ExperimentHub にデータを載せることです。
the annotation hub and the experiment hub are databases with references to the external data
AnnotationHub と ExperimentHub は、ダウンロードする外部データへの参照を持つデータベースです。
for download the hub interfaces provide a querying mechanism on metadata provided at inclusion of the
Hub インターフェイスは、データベースにデータを含めるときに提供されるメタデータへのクエリメカニズムを提供します。
data into the database when using the hub interface for download it already uses bioc
ダウンロードに Hub インターフェイスを使う時、それはすでに
file cache as a caching mechanism so a maintainer does not have to implement it themselves the other
BiocFileCache をキャッシングメカニズムとして使っています。そのためメンテナーはそれを自分で実装する必要はありません。
advantage to listing the data in the hubs is the findability of resources outside of r or outside
Hub にデータを載せることの他の利点は、Rの外部または
the use of the associated bioconductor package there are bioconductor core packages experiment
関連する Bioconductor パッケージの利用外のリソースの見つけやすさです。 Bioconductor のコアパッケージには
hub and annotation hub that can be queried for data of different types or from different sources
ExperimentHub と AnnotationHub があり、それらは異なるタイプの、もしくは異なるソースからのデータをクエリーできます。
the resources can be searched either through a query performed within r or investigation through
リソースは、R内で実行されるクエリまたは
the hub apis and annotationhub.bioconductor.org or experimenthub.bioconductor
annotationhub.bioconductor.org もしくは experimenthub.bioconductor.org での Hub の API を用いた調査のいずれかで検索できます。
the api is admittedly a little crude and we are working on a revamp there's also a
そのAPIは認めざるを得ないことですがまだ粗雑であり、私たちは今改良に取り組んでいます。
shiny version to query hub resources that has been developed and should be announced soon
Hub のリソースをクエリーする Shiny 版もあります。それはまだ開発中でまもなくアナウンスされるはずです。
the query function in r will take a list of terms and return resources matching search criteria
Rのクエリー関数は、用語のリストを取得し、検索条件に一致するリソースを返します。
for example you can see we queried here for ensembl gtf release 103
例えばここでは ensembl、gtf、release-103、そして homo sapiens でクエリーしたところ、
and homo sapiens which returned four results a single bracket using the ahid of interest will
それが4つの結果を返したことが分かるでしょう。興味のある ah_id を用いた角括弧1つの囲みは
give more information on the resource and a double bracket will download and cache the resource
リソースに関する詳細情報を提供します。そして角括弧2重の囲みはリソースをダウンロードしてキャッシュします。
the requirement to add data to the hubs is a package that is already or will be
Hub にデータを追加するための要件は、すでに存在するパッケージもしくは
submitted to bioconductor that includes an inst metadata.csv file with metadata for the
Bioconductorに投稿されるであろうパッケージが、データベースに追加されるであろうリソースのためのメタデータを持つ inst/metadata.csv と、
resources that will be added to the database and an in-script directory with files that indicate
次を示すファイルを持つ inst/script ディレクトリを含んでいることです。
how the data was generated and relevant source information the vignette creating a hub package
それはデータがどのように生成されたか、および関連するソース情報になります。
experiment hub or annotation hub in the core package hub pub describes this in more detail
コアパッケージである HubPub 中の vignette 「Creating A Hub Package: ExperimentHub or AnnotationHub」はこれをもっと詳しく説明しています。
other questions can be directed to the hubs at bioconductor.org email
他の質問は hubs@bioconductor.org にeメールしていただけます。
the hubs currently involve a lot of interaction from the core team we are working on making
Hub は現在、コアチームからの多くのやり取りを含んでいます。
enhancements and restructure to try to make it simpler and easier to submit and maintain hub data
私たちは、それをよりシンプルで簡単にするために、機能強化と再構築に取り組んでいます。
with limited core team interaction currently when data is submitted to the hubs a core team member
それは限られたコアチームの意思疎通で Hub のデータを投稿そして維持するためにです。今のところ、データが Hub に投稿されると、コアチームメンバーが
will evaluate the data and metadata provided if needed assist with uploading data to the
提供されたデータとメタデータを評価し、必要なら
bioconductor provided location again currently that's an amazon s3 bucket but that could change
Bioconductorが提供する場所へのデータのアップロードを支援しています。今のところその場所は Amazon の S3 バケットですが変わる可能性はあります。
and update the database for the metadata provided so the metadata is available
また提供されたメタデータのデータベースを更新し、クエリー関数を使ってメタデータを利用できるようにもしています。
through the query functions additionally core team maintenance of the hubs includes
さらなる Hub のコアチームによるメンテナンスには
managing server code on the amazon web service ec2 instances that hosts the website and api endpoints
AmazonウェブサービスEC2インスタンスでのサーバーコードの管理が含まれます。それはウェブサイトや両方の Hub のAPIエンドポイントをホストするものです。
for both hubs and general core package maintenance of the relevant core packages experiment hub
また次に挙げる関連するコアパッケージの一般的なコアパッケージメンテナンスも含まれます。
annotation hub bioc file cache experiment hub data annotation hub data and hubpub
ExperimentHub、AnnotationHub、BiocFileCache、ExperimentHubData、AnnotationHubData そして HubPub といったものです。
so there are still other core related tasks and infrastructure that we just
他にもまだコアチームに関連するタスクとインフラがまだありますが、
haven't had time to touch on things like the amazon web service resources that we utilize
それらに触れる時間がありませんでした。私たちが利用しているAmazonウェブサービスのリソースですとか、
and the microsoft azure project resources but hopefully this gave everyone an idea
Microsoft の Azure プロジェクトのリソースといったようなものです。
of how much the core team supports in addition to just general core package health and development
ですが恐らくこのトークによって、一般的なコアパッケージのヘルプと開発に加えて、コアチームがどれだけ多くのことをサポートしているかをみなさんに概説できたと思います。
so with that i would like to thank the conference organizers for inviting me to speak it really
それでは、会議の主催者に私を招待してくれたことに感謝します。
has been an honor and thank you to my fellow core team members i appreciate all the work and effort
それはとても光栄なことです。また私の仲間のコアチームメンバーに感謝します。私はすべての仕事と努力に感謝します。
we all put into keeping the project moving forward and most of all a thank you to the
私たちが皆、プロジェクトを前進させ続けることに力を注いでいます。
bioconductor community bioconductor would not be successful without the contributions of all of you
そして、Bioconductor コミュニティのみなさんに心から感謝します。みなさんの貢献が無ければ Bioconductor の成功は無いでしょう。
and whether you're a first time user or a long-time contributor we really hope that you
そして初めてのユーザーであろうと、長年の貢献者であろうと、
found a welcoming and helpful community so please feel free to send me any questions to my email
あなたが Bioconductor を歓迎的で助けになるコミュニティだとを感じていただければ幸いです。それでは気軽に質問があれば送ってください。私のeメールか、
or on the community slack if anyone has any questions about this presentation thank you cheers
コミュニティの Slack に。 どなたでもどんな質問でもこのプレゼンテーションについてのものがあれば。ありがとう みなさん !